- Lorraine - 你終於來了
- Lorraine. - There you are.
我為我的遲到表示歉意
I'm sorry that I'm late.
我正打算給你打電話
I was about to call you.
我深知不該讓一位美麗的女子如此等待
I should know better than to keep a beautiful woman waiting.
你嘴真甜
Oh,laying it on thick,aren't you?
我已經期待多時了
Oh,I've been looking forward to this.
為你準備了一份計劃書
Got a prospectus for you.
先吃飯 你喜歡蟹肉沙拉嗎?
Food first. Do you like crab louie?
- 喜歡 - 這堸絞o簡直棒極了
- I do. - It is so good here.
是用海灣新鮮的石蟹製作的
They use stone crab fresh from the bay.
要是你想吃肉 這兒的肉片也正宗 紅燴牛膝也很棒
The filet is wonderful if you're in the mood for meat,or the osso bucco.
Henry
Henry.
你怎麼了?
Hello.
抱歉
Sorry.
我還在想工作上的事 確認一個客戶的存款
My head is still at work, Making sure I deposited a check for a client.
我現在也你是你的客戶
Well,I'm a client,too.
這會兒我雇著你呢
And you're on my time now.
- 全身心為你服務 - 但願如此
- You have my full attention. - I better.
我有你想要的東西
I have something you want.
只能畫到這個程度嗎?
This is all you have on him?
閉路攝像頭只拍攝到了他的後腦勺 沒任何價值
We have the back of his head from a few cctv angles, Nothing that helps.
他很小心的避開了攝像頭
He's careful to avoid being seen on camera.
我還有很多案子  這傢伙只算是一個小角色
Out of all my cases, this guy was never flagged As top priority,
但這起謀殺案確實很特殊
But this murder changes everything.
你交給我們處理是明智之舉 我們會解釋緣由的
You were right to call us. We'll explain why.
各位  這位是聖地亞哥 高智商犯罪偵查科的Russell Goldman探員
Everyone,this is agent russell goldman From the san diego white collar team.
你已經見過Hotchner探員
You've already met agent hotchner.
這些探員是Rossi Morgan Prentiss Reid
These are agents rossi, morgan,prentiss,and reid.
榮幸之至
A pleasure.
這次是高智商案子?
So we're working a white collar case?
算不上
Not exactly.
我跟蹤一名詐騙犯長達五年
I've been following a con artist for 5 years.
兩天之前 我認為他犯了命案
Two nights ago,I think he killed someone.
Carla Marshall被發現死在邁阿密的家中
Carla marshall of miami was found dead in her home.
勒脖窒息死亡
Asphyxiation by strangulation.
頭部受傷
She also had trauma wounds to the head.
為什麼你覺得是被那騙子所殺?
Why do we think the con man killed her?
上周Carla曾聯繫一個防騙術網站 聲稱自己受騙
Last week carla contacted a fraud website To report a scam.
這份投訴被遞交到了Goldman這
The complaint ended up On goldman's desk.
我們在電話中進行了詳談
We spoke on the phone at length.
她口中的描述 和我盯著的騙子出奇的一致
Her story matched my guy to the "t."
她本打算那天晚上和他對質
She planned on confronting him that night.
我告訴她中斷一切與外界聯繫
I told her to cease all communications
等我過去 我會飛去邁阿密 準備實行誘捕計劃
And wait for me,I'd fly to miami and set up a sting.
但最終計劃泡湯
But that never happened.
你有什麼實質性證據 確定這就是你要的人嗎?
Do you have physical evidence Confirming it's your guy?
還沒 但我和那女人談話當晚她就被殺
No,but for her to be murdered the night that we spoke,
我認為這不是巧合
I don't think it was a coincidence.
沒有任何強行入室 盜竊 性侵犯的跡象
There was no sign of forced entry, theft,or sexual assault.
從犯案手法來看 動機可能是私人原因
And judging from the m.O.,the motive was personal.
- 他的騙術是什麼? - 金融欺詐
- What's his hustle? - Investment fraud.
基本上算是麥道夫一案的山寨版
Basically,he's a smaller madoff.
為了讓大家瞭解 這個騙子的騙術有多高明
To give you an idea of how convincing he is,
這是他過去14年的工作抽樣
This is a sampling of his work going back 14 years.
行騙纍纍啊
He's prolific.
他行騙金額數以千百萬
He's scammed hundreds of thousands of dollars from people,
但從未使用暴力手段
But he's never been violent before.
騙子一般不殺人 如果出了命案 那麼就是為了掩蓋罪行
Con men usually don't murder, but when they do, It's to conceal their crimes.
叫他們騙子 還真抬舉他們
Con man's a nice name for these guys.
從側寫看 他們通常有精神異常
They profile as psychopaths.
他們把手中的騙局視作戲場 把自己視作操縱木偶的傀儡
They see their cons as theater and themselves As a sort of puppeteer.
必須能完全控制受害者 和自己的行騙過程
They have to have absolute control Over their victims and their cons.
也許正是因此他才開始殺人 因為控制不了了?
Maybe that's why he starting killing, Because he lost control?
關鍵是 有多失控?
The question is,how out of control is he?
如果他加速失控 那麼他周圍的人都有危險
Well,if he's spiraling, he's a danger to everyone around him.
因為魅力出眾 所以受害者根本無法覺察
And because he's so charming, The victims never see it coming.
我這錢要給誰?
Who do I make it out to?
Grant Dale投資公司
Grant dale investments,inc.
Hunter Portland咨詢有限公司
Hunter portland advisors,incorporated.
Henry Moffet對沖基金有限公司
Henry moffet hedge funds,incorporated.
Henry Moffet... 對沖基金... 有限公司
Henry moffet... Hedge funds... Inc.
可有不少錢呢
This is a lot of money.
絕對會成為你一生中最明智的決定
It'll be the best decision of your life.
犯罪心理 第五季 第14集 寄生蟲
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode14 Parasite
"若吾即本我 後又失本我 然我為何人"
"if I am what I have, "and if I lose what I have, Who,then,am I?"
德國心理學家 Erich Fromm
German psychologist erich fromm.
難以置信 你們居然有專機
I can't believe you guys have your own jet.
我們輪流駕駛 你要不也試試?
We take turns piloting. You want to give her a try?
- 真的?  - 逗你玩呢
- Really? - No.
他使用了什麼反偵查手段 掩蓋自己的作案痕跡?
What kind of forensic countermeasures does he use To hide his trail?
偽造的身份證 一次性手機   已付費信用卡 異國銀行戶頭
Fake I.D.S,disposable phones, Prepaid credit cards,foreign bank accounts.
你追查不到他的海外賬戶嗎?
You can't track his accounts overseas?
可以 但要很長時間才能拿到銀行記錄
We can,but it takes months to get the records,
他寥寥數秒 就可以把錢轉了又轉
And it only takes him seconds To transfer money again and again.
查到巴哈馬群島的時候
By the time you figure out it's in the bahamas,
他已經把錢轉到瑞士或其他地方了
He's already moved it to switzerland or somewhere else.
他總能遙遙領先
I've always been too far behind him.
因為Carla的案子 我們現在離他近一點了
Well,we're a lot closer now because of carla.
最初是什麼引起了她的懷疑?
What made her suspicious in the first place?
她得把父親送進養老院
She needed to get her father into a retirement home,
當她聯繫這位"Grant Dale" 想要回自己的投資時
And when she called this guy grant dale to free up her money,
他沒有回她的電話
He never returned her phone calls.
騙子的本能是腳底抹油 而不是投入戰鬥
A con man's first instinct is flight,not fight.
他的殺人動機不是圖財   而是心理需求
What makes him kill, though,isn't financial, It's psychological.
我們需要關注的是 為何選Carla 為何是此時下手?
That's what we need to concentrate on. Why carla and why now?
Morgan和Prentiss 去她家看看
Morgan and prentiss,go to her house.
Goldman探員 為何不一起去呢?
Agent goldman,why don't you join them.
我把他的案子卷宗發回外勤辦事處了
I sent his case files to the field office.
需要我留下來幫你們查看案卷嗎?
Shouldn't I stay with you and help you sift through them?
我希望能獨立查看  得出我們自己的理論
I'd like to go through them independently, Come up with our own theories,
看是否能發現什麼行為模式 能夠讓我們搶先他一步
See if any behavioral patterns emerge That'll help us get ahead of him.
佛羅里達州 邁阿密 FBI外勤辦事處
******
- Goldman的案卷在走廊盡頭的房間 - 謝謝
- Agent goldman's files are in that room down the hall. - Thank you.
- 有什麼需要請叫我 - 謝謝
- Let me know if you need anything. - Thank you.
開什麼玩笑
You're kidding me.
我們要看完這麼多?
We have to go through all of this?
高智商犯罪總會留下書面記錄
White collar cases often come down to a paper trail.
也許不會很糟糕 至少很有條理
Maybe it won't be so bad. I mean,at least it's well organized.
這是他的活  在桌子前坐上一天 查看書面證據
That's his job. He sits at a desk all day And accumulates paper evidence.
好了 Dave你研究受害者
All right. Dave,you work victimology.
Reid 看能否找出他的行程模式
Reid,see if you can find anything in his travel patterns.
JJ 我們一起在黑板上畫個時間軸
Jj,let's get a timeline up on the board.
她是個房產經紀人
She was a real estate agent.
她一個人過得很好  直到William走進她的生活
She was doing well for herself Until william came into her life.
為什麼這麼稱呼他?
Why do you call him that?
在他早期的行騙中 他好幾次自稱是Bill Billy或者Will
He introduced himself as bill, billy,or will Several times in his early cons.
我猜他的真名可能是William這種類型的
My guess is that his real name May be some form of william.
他的大部分受害者都很富有 對吧?
So most of his victims were very wealthy,right?
你該瞧瞧他們的豪宅
You should see some of their mansions.
我轉悠了一圈 這房子很不錯 但不算豪華
Well,I'm looking around this house and it's nice, But no mansion.
她的投資沒像其他客戶那麼多
She didn't invest as much as his other clients either.
我好奇他為什麼盯上她
I wonder why he targeted her.
可能在其他方面對他有用
She may have been useful to him in some other way.
嘿 Goldman  他對Carla行騙時 使用的別名是?
Hey,goldman. What was the alias he was using with carla?
- Grant Dale - 來看看這個
- Grant dale. - Come check this out.
- 他建了個網站 - 警察怎麼沒有發現這個?
- He set up a website. - Why didn't the detectives find this before?
當地警察不會想到去找這個
The locals wouldn't know to look for it.
只有一個頁面 普通的投資信息
Well,it's only one page. Generic investment information.
既沒有聯繫方式 也沒有他的照片
I mean,there's no contacts, there's no picture of himself.
是沒有 只有漂亮汽車和房子的照片
No,just photos of nice cars and houses.
他在兜售成功的夢想
So he's selling the fantasy of success.
他的網站頁面很簡單 像是個標準模板
His web design is pretty basic. I mean,it's like a standard template.
很簡單就能建成
It would be fairly easy to set up.
- 可能是他還建了其他網站 - 我給Garcia打電話
- Maybe he created others. - I'm gonna call garcia.
親愛的 是我 我開了免提
Hey,baby girl,it's me. You're on speaker.
親愛的呀 誰聽不重要 反正每次都是你~
Oh,sug,I don't care who hears it. It's always been you.
聽好 我剛給你發了鏈接
Listen,I just emailed you a link.
- 收到了 - 是不明嫌犯的網站
- Got it. - It's the unsub's website.
你是不是想讓我查他怎麼支付 然後找到他的行蹤?
Do you want me to find out how he paid For his hosting services, track him down that way?
最終都會回到同一個止回序列
We'll run into the same backstopping trail.
你說的沒錯 這個確實無法跟蹤
Oh,you are right. That's untraceable.
好吧 不管這個了 你能不能查一下有相同內容的網站?
All right,we'll forget that. Can you do a search for websites Containing the same content?
查詢中...
And searching... And searching...
有一個...兩個...一共九個相同網站 一樣的文字內容 一樣的圖片
There are 1,2-- 9 identical websites, Same written content,same pictures,
除了名字不一樣
Just different names.
都是新的假名
These are all new aliases.
他從來沒有同時用過10個 這些都是新的
And he's never had 10 at once. This is all new.
- 我是Henry Moffet - 你騙了我
- I'm henry moffet. - You lied to me about everything.
你說什麼?
What are you talking about?
你的名字不是Grant Dale
Your name is not grant dale.
你為什麼要這樣對我?
God,why are you doing this to me?
- 冷靜 聽我說 - 不 你走吧
- Just calm down. Listen to me. - No,just leave.
你都不給我機會解釋
You're not giving me a chance to explain.
滾 不然我就報警了!
Leave or I'll call the police!
Grant...
我是Henry Moffet
I'm henry moffet.
Henry Moffet
Henry moffet.
CIA最多會給每個特工2-3個假名
The cia assigns an agent 2 or 3 aliases at most.
再多了就容易搞混了
Any more than that, And it's difficult to keep the names straight.
而這個人有10個假名
This guy's juggling 10.
活在十種不同的生活中 多少要有些分裂了
Being all these people,that's gotta start Fracturing him somehow.
如果他的記憶過度緊張 這有可能造成他的失控
If his memory is strained, it could be causing him to lose control.
我們找到了他現在使用的假名 我們只需要找到客戶是誰
We have the current aliases. We just need to know who the clients are.
拿到了Carla的通話記錄
Got carla's phone records.
她死的那天晚上 給一個未知號碼打了很多次電話
She made several calls To an unknown number the night she died.
我追蹤了這個號碼 是一次性手機 那之後就沒有用過
I tracked the number. It was a disposable phone That hasn't been used since.
那應該是不明嫌犯的號碼
That's gotta be the unsub's number.
他殺了她之後就把電話扔了
He tossed it after he killed her.
之前幾個月 她很有規律地在很晚的時候 給這個號碼打電話
Over the past few months, She routinely called this number Really late at night.
- 有多晚? - 深夜
- How late? - Like bedtime late.
不會有人在深夜和投資經理談生意的
You don't do business with your investment manager at bedtime.
那我們什麼時候再來過?
So,when are we gonna do this again?
我老公快回來了 所以...
My husband's coming home,so...
一段時間內我不會再見到你了
I won't see you for a while.
Grant...我會想你的 你騙了我
I'll miss you...grant. You lied to me About everything.
滾 否則我就報警!
Leave or I'll call the police!
Grant 你還好麼?
Grant,are you ok?
Henry 你還好麼?
Henry,are you ok?
我也會想你的
I'm gonna miss you,too.
Carla從來沒有提過和他有外遇?
So carla never mentioned anything about an affair with him?
沒有 但是要讓詐騙案受害人願意合作 是很難的
No,but it's always been a challenge with fraud victims To be totally forthcoming.
他們覺得被騙是很丟人的 他們通常都會有所隱瞞
They're so embarrassed about being duped, They don't tell you everything.
Goldman探長
Detective goldman.
- 我們想對比一下你的記錄 - 說吧
- We'd like to compare notes. - Shoot.
我在進行受害者研究
I'm looking at the victimology.
我們管這個叫喜好群體 一個意思
We say affinity groups. Same thing.
指的是有相同愛好的受害者
It refers to victims with shared interests.
好的 既然是在你們的領域 那就用你們的叫法
Ok. We're in your world, we'll use your terms.
你的檔案指出了他在前幾個案子中 的喜好群體
Your files point to specific affinity groups he targeted In the first few cities.
- 這個在你看來足夠具體麼? - 足夠具體
- Does this look accurate to you? - Yes,it does.
他離開聖迭戈之後 他的受害人就遍佈全國了
Once he got beyond san diego, His victims are all over the place.
沒有相同點
No shared interests.
我也是這麼個結論
I came to the same conclusions.
他不再使用喜好群體來挑選目標 他找到了其他的方法
So he stopped using affinity groups And found his victims somewhere else.
- 可是我不知道是用什麼方法 - 這也是我們要研究的
- Where,I don't know. - That's where we start.
佛羅里達州 勞德代爾堡
******
我是Randy Randy Randy
I'm randy. Randy. Randy.
我是Randy Summerland
I'm randy summerland.
幫我們多賺點錢 知道嗎?
Make us some money,ok?
沒問題
I can do that.
再說遍 你的名字怎麼拼?
Now,how do I spell your name,again?
M-o-f-f-e-t Henry Moffet 對沖基金 有限公司
M-o-f-f-e-t. Henry moffet hedge funds,incorporated.
Henry Moffet是誰?
Who is henry moffet?
Randy 誰是Henry Moffet?
Randy... Who is henry moffet?
我搭檔
It's my partner.
- 你從沒提過你有搭檔 - 沒有嗎?
- You didn't mention anything about a partner. - I didn't?
而且我上次的支票也不是兌給他的
And this isn't who I made the check out to last time.
他和我搭檔有幾年了
He's been my partner for years.
那我為什麼要付錢給他?
Then why am I making the check out to him?
理由很簡單
There's a simple explanation.
所以 不明疑犯和被害人在喝酒
So,the unsub and the vic are having drinks.
被害人拿出了支票簿和筆  寫上了日期 就只有這些
The vic has a checkbook and pen out, Check's dated,but that's it.
不明疑犯的錢就快到手了  可不知怎麼沒拿到 於是就下殺手了
The unsub got that close to getting his money, Somehow failed,and then did this.
這可是過度殺害 他把他的頭都砸爛了
And this is overkill. He bashed his head in.
他已經完全精神錯亂了 而且惡化地很快
He's completely unhinged and devolving fast.
可他自己還不知道
Only he doesn't know that.
他還想要工作  他不知道自己隨時都可能失去控制
He's still trying to go to work And he doesn't know he's in danger of losing it at any minute.
就像功能性酗酒者
Like a functioning alcoholic.
不明嫌犯把所有的精力 都投在了這些騙局上
The unsub channels all of his energy into these cons,
一旦騙局失敗 這就是他的應對
And when the con falls apart, This is how he handles it.
你認識Randy多久了?
How long have you known randy?
過去幾個月 我們和他經常在一起
We spent a lot of time with him In the last couple of months.
他幫我們投資
He was helping us invest.
你們給了他多少錢?
How much money did you give to him?
他一直說 在市場上我們需要積極
He just kept saying we needed to be aggressive in this market.
我的天 這都是我的錯
Oh,my god, This is all my fault.
- 什麼意思? - 是我認識的Randy
- What do you mean? - I met randy.
是我把這個男人引入了我們的生活
I brought this man into our lives.
Mckelson夫人 你和Randy之間還有其他的關係嗎?
Mrs. Mckelson, Is there anything more to your relationship With randy?
最終我們都會發現的
We're gonna find out eventually.
發現什麼?
Find out what?
他所說的Randy並不是他自己
Randy wasn't who he said he was.
- 甚至Randy這名字也不是真實的 - 什麼?
- Randy wasn't even his real name. - What?
我們認為這個男人 利用自己的長相和魅力來引誘女人
We think this man is using his looks and his charm To target women.
所以說還有其他人咯
So there's others.
我居然和一個殺我丈夫的男人上床
I laid in bed next to the man Who killed my husband.
他們有私情嗎?
Did they have transgressions?
這事讓她快崩潰了
She's pretty beat up over it.
Randy 誰是Henry Moffet?
Randy,who is henry moffet?
爸爸?
Daddy?
你回來啦!
You're home!
嘿 早上好啊 夥計
Hey,good morning,buddy.
讓我看看你
let me look at you.
你可真是個帥小伙 你發現沒?
You're a handsome devil,you know that?
- 我想你了 - 我也想你了
- I missed you. - I missed you,too.
Bill 你什麼時候回來的?
Bill,when did you get in?
- 就剛才 - 出差怎麼樣?
- Just now. - How was your trip?
- 不怎麼樣 - 抱歉 出什麼事了?
- It didn't really pan out. - Sorry. What happened?
我們能等JD去了學校再談嗎?
Can we,uh,talk about this after j.D. Goes to school?
我要吃薄餅
I want pancakes.
真的? 你要吃?
Really? You do?
成 那就給你薄餅吃
Well,then pancakes you shall have.
你不會覺得很帶勁吧?
You're not enjoying this,are you?
我喜歡在文件塈雿u索 讓我易於思考
I like a good paper trail. I find it meditative.
要你正常一次就那麼難嗎?
Is it really that hard for you to be normal just one time?
他又毀了另一個化名
He just burned another alias.
要是這人決定了要銷毀所有的化名
You know,if this guy's on a mission To eliminate all these aliases,
他會有系統地殺掉他的受害人
He's gonna systematically assassinate his victims.
Carla住在邁阿密
Carla lived in miami.
這次的被害人Frank Mckelson 住在勞德代爾堡北部
This victim,frank mckelson, lived north in ft. Lauderdale.
南佛羅里達都有可能出現被害人
The victims could be anywhere in south florida.
如果他是因為經濟形勢而加緊行騙
If he's working harder because of the economy,
那他擴大活動範圍就說得通了
It makes sense that he would expand his operating zone.
Prentiss和Rossi快回來了 我們需要給出側寫
Prentiss and rossi are on their way back. We need to give the profile.
關於聖迭戈 這還有些問題
There's something else about san diego.
我發覺在他早期的案例中  他平均每個城市只待14到18個月
I noticed in his earlier crimes he only stays in each city An average of 14 to 18 months.
而他在聖迭戈待了3年半 然後再沒有在相同的城市待這麼久
Then he's in san diego for 3 1/2 years And then never in the same city for that long again.
聖迭戈有什麼 會讓他待這麼久?
All right,so what is it about san diego that made him stay longer?
繼續查下去 Reid 看看有什麼線索
Keep following that,reid. See where it takes us.
你確定?
Are you sure?
要是有選擇 我就不會搬了
I wouldn't be doing this if we didn't have to.
JD才開始交新朋友
J.D.Was just starting to make new friends.
你要我怎麼樣? 這堣w經沒什麼錢賺了
What do you want me to do? The money has dried up here.
也許你可以休個假 多花些時間和JD在一起
Maybe you could take a break, Spend more time with j.D.
沒有足夠的客戶 你讓我怎麼養家?
Ok,then how am I supposed to raise a family If I don't have enough clients?
寶貝 我不想看到你壓力這麼大
Baby,I hate seeing you so stressed out.
我知道 可現在的經濟形勢快讓我崩潰了
All right,now,this economy is killing me.
- 我可以也去找份工作的 - 不
- I can get a job,too. - No.
不用 我一個人養得起我們
No,I can take care of us myself.
可我們得想個辦法 因為我不想再搬了
Well,we have to figure something out, because I don't want to move again.
聽好 我們搬去波士頓 沒有商量餘地
Listen,we are moving to boston. End of discussion.
親愛的 怎麼弄的?
Honey,what happened?
現在去整理東西吧
Now start packing.
不明疑犯是一名高智商詐騙犯 行為分析者將其表現出的人格
This unsub is a white collar con man Who embodies what behaviorists call the dark triad--
稱為黑色三要素 自戀 權術主義 以及異常的自我推銷
Narcissism, Machiavellianism, And aberrant self-promotion.
也就是說 這個人以自我為中心
What that means is that everything revolves around this guy.
他使用不正當的手段控制和剝削他人
He manipulates and exploits others using dishonest tactics,
他已經對社會構成威脅
And he's become a menace to society.
Hunter Hunter Hunter
Hunter. Hunter. Hunter.
我叫Hunter Portland
I'm hunter portland.
也就是我們常說的卡薩諾瓦式騙子 (意大利冒險家 風流成性)
He's also what we call a casanova con man.
他勾引女人以獲取錢財
He seduces women to get to their money.
他通常和多數對像不定期發生性關係
It's standard behavior for him To have casual sex with multiple partners
然後以此作為工具來達到目標
And then use that as a weapon to accomplish his goals.
我們有他的素描
We have his sketch.
這板上的是他的化名
And here on the board are his aliases.
他時常出現在高級會場 鄉間俱樂部 賓館酒吧以及會員制的機構
He frequents high-end venues-- Country clubs,hotel bars, and membership-only establishments.
通知銀行
And notify the banks.
他經常轉移錢財 不斷開戶銷戶
He's constantly moving money, Opening and closing bank accounts.
他活躍在邁阿密和勞德代爾堡 不過也有可能出現在其他富裕的社區
He's active in miami and ft. Lauderdale, But he could be in other wealthy communities,too.
留意一下 波卡瑞頓 或者珊瑚頂市這樣的地方
Look at places like boca raton Or coral gables.
他現在頭腦中有太多的化名 讓他開始精神分裂
He has too many aliases in his head right now And it's causing him to fracture mentally.
這樣的失控激發了他的暴力 讓他變得危險
And it's this loss of control That triggers his violence and makes him dangerous to be around.
任何額外的壓力都會增加他攻擊的可能性
And any additional stress Will make him more likely to attack.
我用不著隔這麼久才見你一次的
I don't have to go this long without seeing you.
我可以搭飛機去你那
I could fly to wherever you are.
你會讓我分心的
you would just distract me.
我們會整天都膩在床上
We'd just be spending all day in bed together.
我丈夫這個禮拜不在
My husband's gone for a week.
你今晚為什麼不留下來?
Why don't you stay tonight?
我...不行 美人
I--I can't,gorgeous.
我得趕在閉市之前把你的支票存進銀行
I got to deposit your check in the bank before the market closes.
你覺得我們在一起能幸福嗎?
Do you think that we could be happy together?
什麼?
What?
我可以離開我丈夫
I could leave my husband.
慢一點
Slow down.
Hunter Hunter 別接
Hunter. Hunter,not now.
這個我非接不可
I gotta--I gotta take this.
你好?
Hello?
別生氣 我想要回我的支票
Don't be mad at me, but I want my check back.
什麼?
What?
- 我有電話進來 先別掛 - 別...
- I got another call. Uh,don't go anywhere. - No--
- Bill - 對 是我
- Bill-- - Yes,I'm here.
我要你去Tod那接下JD 然後送他去上鋼琴課
I need you to pick up j.D.From tod's And drop him off at piano.
我現在不行
No,I can't.
我的車壞了 幫我個忙
My car broke down. Help me out here.
知道了
Fine.
嘿
Hello.
Henry 真的很抱歉 我只是... 我不想再進一步了
Henry,I'm really sorry,I just-- I don't want to move forward.
聽著 我可以擔保你的錢
Look,I can guarantee your money.
為什麼 什麼意思?
Why,what do you mean?
我不是對每個人都這樣的 不過既然是你 我不會讓你冒風險的
Well,I don't do this for just anybody, But since it's you,I can,uh, protect you from any risk.
我晚點去接你 到時候我們再談 好嗎?
I'll pick you up in a little bit and we'll talk about it,ok?
好的 Henry
Ok,henry.
Hunter?
- 我要你仔細聽我說 - 好
- I need you to listen to me. - Ok.
我懷孕了
I'm pregnant.
是你的
It's yours.
- Grant Dale - Bill
- Grant dale. - Bill.
Jareau探員說你有發現
Agent jareau said you have something.
我和他的受害者談過
I spoke to his victims.
在去聖迭戈之前  說他開得是很靚的跑車
Before san diego,they described him As driving exotic sports cars.
聖迭戈之後  說他開的是越野車和商務車
After san diego, they described him as driving Larger sedans and suvs.
聖迭戈之前 他住單身公寓 典型的單身貴族
Before san diego, He lived in condos, referred to them as bachelor pads.
聖迭戈之後  他住進了有花園的封閉式社區
After san diego,spoke of living in gated communities With large yards.
是什麼讓男人在一個地方久留 降低車的品味 提升房子的要求?
What forces a man to stay put in one place for a while, Downgrade his car,upgrade his house?
你認為他有家室?
You think he has a family?
這是晉陞為父親後的 生活方式的轉變
These are lifestyle changes a new dad would make.
他為什麼要成家?
Why would he start a family?
因為他想裝成普通人 家庭能讓精神病人看起來像正常人
Because he wants to appear normal, And a family does that for a psychopath.
妻子承擔看門人或主婦的角色
Wives usually serve a purpose, As a caretaker or homemaker.
後代是他們的自我衍生 同時滿足他們的自戀情節
They value their offspring As an extension of themselves And it also feeds their narcissistic ego.
很有趣的理論 這些能幫到我們嗎?
These are interesting theories, But how does this help us?
為逃避法律責任 騙子會把所有東西都掛在妻子名下
As a forensic countermeasure, Con men put everything in their wives' names.
銀行賬號 汽車 房子
Bank accounts,cars,homes.
如果他妻子沒有參與犯罪 她會一直使用真名
And if his wife isn't complicit in his crimes, She'll still be using her real name.
找到了他妻子 就找到了不明嫌犯
If we find the wife, We can find the unsub.
謝謝你 謝謝你的酒水 謝謝你擔保我的錢
Thank you,for the drink And for guaranteeing my money.
一切都會沒問題的
It's all gonna work out.
我只是有點害怕
I just got scared.
我明白
I understand.
你按錯按鈕了
You pressed the wrong button.
爸爸?
Dad?
Daddy?
嘿 我在
Hey,that's me.
能跟你談件事嗎?
Can I talk to you about something?
當然可以 寶貝
Yeah,of course,buddy.
我們又要搬家嗎? 我喜歡這
Do we have to move again? I like it here.
我對你真的很失望
You know,I'm really disappointed in you.
對不起
Sorry.
我失望時因為你沒有早點開口
I'm really disappointed because you didn't say something sooner.
生命中需要的東西 你必須開口要
You know,if you want something in life, As a man,you need to ask for it.
- 就當是學了一課 - 好的
- Now,let that be a lesson. - Ok.
你真的喜歡這 小伙子?
So you really like it here,huh,big guy?
是的
Yeah.
也許我能想個法子 在這埵h待一陣
Well,I think I may have found a way For us to stay for a while.
- 真的? - 是的
- Serious? - yeah.
我只要丟掉舊的客戶名單  然後重新開始
I just need to dump my client list and start over.
那麼我們能留在這?
So we can stay?
我會為你做任何事情 寶貝
I'd do anything for you,kiddo.
那是什麼?
What is that?
在這塈中@會兒 好嗎?
Just hang out here for a sec,all right?
看會兒動畫片
Watch your video.
怎麼回事?
What is it?
備用輪胎鬆動了
Spare tire came loose.
別擔心
Don't worry.
我能修好
I'm fixing it.
頭部多處重傷 和其他人一樣
Massive blunt force trauma to the head, Same as the others.
把她丟在這埵釵韞庢N?
Does it make sense for him to dump her like this?
他兩天內連殺兩人
He's killed 2 people in 2 days.
他的分裂癥狀劇增
His fracturing is intensifying.
罪犯心理惡化到這種程度  什麼事都做的出來
When a criminal devolves like this, They're capable of anything.
JJ說有人報案 說他老婆昨晚失蹤了
Jj said a man reported his wife missing last night.
描述和死者符合 名叫Lorraine Horton
Description matches the body. Name's lorraine horton.
瞭解她的投資歷史嗎?
Do we know anything about her investment history?
小組正在查
The team's looking into it right now.
他在邁阿密殺了第一名受害者 然後離開
Ok,so he killed his first victim in miami and then left town,
來到勞德代爾堡 殺害第2名受害者 並沒有離開 而是殺了第3人
Came to ft.Lauderdale, killed his second victim here, But he didn't leave town for his third.
留在勞德代爾堡有什麼重要事情?
Is there a significance to him staying in ft. Lauderdale?
夥計們 也許他的家人住在這?
Guys,what if his family lives here?
所以他才要消除這堛澈簪
That's why he's trying to eliminate threats to himself here,
因為他的家在這 他需要保護自己的身份
'cause this is his home where he needs to protect his identity.
嘿 Garcia
Hey,garcia.
Em 我感覺自己被派到野外狩獵了
Em,I feel like I've been sent on a wild snipe hunt.
知道南佛羅里達有多少女人 租用豪華車和高級公寓嗎?
Do you have any idea how many women in south florida Lease luxury cars and rent mansions?
我告訴你 很多 這就是答案
I will answer. Too many. That's how many.
把搜索範圍縮小到勞德代爾堡
Ok,narrow the search down to ft. Lauderdale only.
搜索8到12個月之前搬來這堛漱k人
Look at women who moved here 8 to 12 months ago,
看是否有人在聖迭戈出現過
See if any of them have any history with san diego.
好的 等我找到隱蔽獵物後再打給你
Ok. I'll call you back when I find the elusive snipe creature.
這對我們有好處
This is gonna be good for us.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我還以為你會高興
I thought you would be happy.
昨天你還堅持要馬上搬走
Just yesterday you were hel l-bent on moving us immediately.
是的 但是你和JD都說要待在這 所以我想了個法子留下來
Yeah,and then you and j.D.Both said you wanted to stay, So I found a way to make it happen.
怎麼做的?
How?
我做到了
I just did.
你到底怎麼回事?
What is going on with you?
知道嗎?
You know what?
我還以為哄你開心了 我可沒時間和你糾纏這個
I thought I was doing you a favor. I don't have time for this.
下午好
Good afternoon.
我是Stuart 是你們要找銀行經理?
I'm stuart. You asked for the bank manager?
我們是FBI的Rossi探員和Jareau探員
Agents rossi and jareau,fbi.
我們需要一個叫 Lorraine Horton客戶的資料
We need some information on a client named lorraine horton.
Horton女士沒事吧?
Is ms. Horton ok?
能否查看下她最近的銀行業務 看是否有不尋常的地方?
Can you check her recent banking activities, See if there's anything unusual?
比如給某人的公司開了張支票
Maybe a check written to a person's corporation.
我知道她最近得了一大筆錢
I know she recently came into more money.
她媽媽去世後 老房子賣了個好價錢
Her mother passed. They sold the house And she got a pretty good sum for it.
- 她賣了房子? - 是的 長官
- She sold a house? - Yes,sir.
第1個受害者是搞房產的吧?
Wasn't the first victim in real estate?
我們一直在問 他是怎麼找到受害者的
We've been asking ourselves How he finds his victims now.
Lorraine出售她母親的房子 發了一大筆意外之財
We just found out lorraine got a large windfall From selling her mother's house.
Carla Marshall 第一位受害者 是位房產經紀人
Carla marshall,the first victim, Was in real estate.
出售一所房子 你的財產成了公開的記錄
When you sell a house, your property becomes public record.
你的名字會出現在各種名單上
Your name goes on these lists.
領頭經紀人編輯名單後 出售給房產公司
Lists compiled by lead brokers And sold to the real estate companies.
嘿 Pen
Hey,pen.
噢 夥計 我這堨i是天上掉餡餅了
Oh,man,it is raining snipe all up in here.
知道那個船東Frank和Dina Mckelson 8個月前賣了夏威夷的一所房子嗎?
Did you know that your boat owners frank and dina mckelson Sold a house in hawaii about 8 months ago?
他們誰和Carla Marshall有直接聯繫嗎?
Do any of them have a direct connection to carla marshall?
啊 Carla 為她公司出售的 海濱公寓撰寫廣告詞
Ah,carla generated these letters Advertising the swanky beachfront condos Her company sells--
聽好了-- Lorraine Horton  今天早上遇害的女士
stay with me-- Lorraine horton,the lady who was murdered this morning,
她的地址 和Mckelsons的地址
Her address,along with the mckelsons' address,
深埋在Carla手提電腦堛漪Y個表格
Are buried in a spreadsheet in carla's laptop.
不明嫌犯就是這樣尋找受害者的 他利用Carla找到肥羊
That's how the unsub found his victims. He used carla to get her leads.
所以才盯上她
That's why he targeted her.
她能讓他得到 有大筆流動資產的人的名單
She gave him access to a list of people With a large amount of liquid assets.
- 我們需要這份名單 - 已經在傳給你了
- We need that list. - Already flying to you.
不僅如此 夥計們  我可能找到他老婆了
But that is not all,folks. I think I may have found the wife.
我搜索了過去8-12個月  住在勞德代爾堡
I did I search on women who've lived in ft. Lauderdale For the last 8 to 12 months,
租有大房子和豪華汽車的女人 並且曾經在聖迭戈待過
Who rent houses and cars and have a history in san diego.
搜到了一打的名字 但是...
Came up with about a dozen names,but...
- 其中只有一人在房產公司工作 - 誰?
- Ooh,la la,only one of them works in real estate. - Who?
Rebecca Hodges
Her name's rebecca hodges.
有個9歲的兒子 John Davison Hodges 出生在聖迭戈
She has a 9-year-old son, John davison hodges,born in san diego,
出生證明上的父親名字是William Hodges
Father on birth certificate Listed as william hodges.
William
William.
我有她租來的房子地址
I got the address of the house she's renting,too.
我們去那邊  Morgan 去學校接孩子
Let's head over there. Morgan,pull the son out of school.
JJ和Reid 查看名單上的潛在受害者
Jj and reid,go over the list of potential victims.
如果有人認識不明嫌犯 派一隊人過去
If anybody knows the unsub, send units to them.
好的 我要去見那個客戶了
Ok,so I'm gonna go deal with this client.
待會兒給我打電話嗎?
Will you call me later?
會的
Yeah,I will.
你落下啥東西了?
Did you forget something?
- 你是Bill的客戶嗎? - 誰?
- Are you a client of bill's? - Who?
別裝蒜 我剛剛看見他離開
Don't do that. I saw him leaving here.
我不知道你在說什麼 請走開
I don't know what you're talking about. You should leave.
我看見你和我丈夫在一起 你知道我們已經有兒子了嗎?
I saw you with my husband. Do you know we have a son?
他叫JD
His name is j.D.
你不知道Bill已經結婚了?
You didn't know bill was married?
我不知道他叫Bill
I didn't know his name was bill.
還是我 Jareau探員
Again,this is agent jareau.
事情很緊急 請給我回電話 謝謝
It's very important that you call me back. Thank you.
謝謝 是的 非常感謝
Thank you. Yeah,thanks so much.
我剛確認了另一名潛在受害者 派了一隊人過去
I just confirmed another potential victim. I sent a unit over.
我聯繫不上這對夫婦  Hector和Brooke Sanchez
I can't get ahold of this one couple, Hector and brooke sanchez.
- 快點 - 爸爸 我們去哪?
- Hurry up. - Dad,where are we going?
我們去接媽媽 是個驚喜
We're going to get mom. It's a surprise.
- 什麼樣的驚喜? - 我們要去波士頓了
- What kind of surprise? - We're going to boston.
但是你昨天還說...
But you said yesterday--
上車去 好嗎? 快點
Just get in the car,ok?Hurry up.
你知道自己緊張的時候會摳指甲嗎?
Do you know you pick your nails when you're anxious?
我從沒搭過局堛漕T車 去追一個殺手
I've never been in a bureau car chasing a killer before.
準備好和William見面了嗎?
You ready to meet william face to face?
總算給我等到了
It's about damn time.
- 爸爸 我們去哪? - 安靜
- Dad,where are you going? - Quiet.
閉上嘴 讓我好好想想
Just shut up and let me think.
爸爸...
Daddy...
對不起 寶貝 我不是故意嘲你嚷的
I'm sorry,kiddo. I didn't mean to yell at you.
媽媽在哪?
Where's mommy?
問得好
That's a good question.
是他打來的
That's him calling.
別接
Well,don't answer it.
我們得談談
We need to talk.
我懷孕了 是他的
I am pregnant. It's his.
我的上帝啊
Oh,my god.
快接啊
Come on,pick up.
我們去...
Ok,we're going to,uh...
我們先去別的地方轉轉  等你媽媽回電話 好嗎?
Go hang out somewhere and wait for mommy to call back,all right?
好的
Ok.
之前的那對夫妻怎麼說?
What about that one couple from earlier?
辦公室的人說丈夫出城了  我還沒有聯繫到妻子
His office said he's out of town. I haven't been able to get ahold of her yet.
是Morgan 嗨Morgan
it's morgan. Hey,morgan.
Reid 聽著 我在他兒子的學校
Yeah,reid,listen,I'm at the son's school.
校長說JD Hodges  45分鐘前就被接走了
Principal says that j.D. Hodges Was pulled out of class 45 minutes ago.
- 誰接的? - 不明疑犯
- By who? - The unsub.
他們現在可是心慌意亂啊 孩子
They're in the wind,kid.
他會想盡辦法和他的家人一起離開
He's gonna try and leave with his family.
好的 謝謝 我會告訴其他人的
All right,thanks,I'll let everyone know.
- Garcia? - 什麼事 J?
- Garcia? - What up,jj?
能查出Rebecca Hodges有沒有帶手機嗎?
Can you find out if rebecca hodges has a cell phone?
我們想通過手機信號確定她現在的位置
We want to try and track where she is right now.
稍等
Uno momento.
- 有點不對勁 - 怎麼了?
- Something's weird. - What?
妻子的名下註冊了兩部手機
The wife has 2 cell phones listed in her name.
一個是她自己的 一個是她丈夫的?
One could be hers,one could be his?
他把號碼全都註冊在她的名下
He put them both in her name.
是的 但是現在兩部手機信號 都在同一地區很活躍
Yeah,but they're both active in the same quadrant right now.
哪?
Where?
某個勞德代爾堡的高級住宅區
Some posh ft. Lauderdale neighborhood.
等一下
Wait a second.
在我們潛在受害人名單上 有一對夫妻就在這個區域
A couple on our potential victims list lives in the same area.
Hector 和 Brooke Sanchez
Hector and brooke sanchez.
那就是我聯繫不上的女人
That's the woman I can't get ahold of.
- Hotch - 知道了 Reid
- Hotch. - Ok,got it,reid.
所有人都去Sanchez家 謝謝
Direct everyone to the sanchez house. Thanks.
妻子在受害人家媟F什麼?
What's the wife doing at a victim's house?
難道我們想錯了? 你覺得她是共犯麼?
Were we wrong about her? Do you think she's complicit?
我不覺得 如果是的話  他會在行騙過程中利用她的
I don't think so. If she was, he'd use her in the con.
他說他叫Hunter Portland
He told me his name was hunter portland.
你們來往有多久了?
How long have you been seeing him?
我們一起到聖克魯瓦度假
We vacationed in st. Croix together.
- 什麼? 什麼時候? - 上個月
- What? When? - Last month.
他說他在波士頓出差
He said he was in boston on a business trip.
Brooke 你在這?
Brooke,you here?
- 你肯定覺得我是個白癡 - 不是的
- You must think I'm an idiot. - It's not true.
你怎麼能這麼對待你的家庭?
How could you do this to your family?
我為這個家提供了一切
I provide everything for my family.
這些日子 你全都是為了我的錢?
Were you just after my money this whole time?
不 不 我跟你說過了 我會照顧你的
No. No,I told you I was gonna take care of you.
你每次說你去出差 還有其他女人麼?
All those times you traveled for work-- Are there other women?
- 天啊 你到底在幹嗎? - 爸爸?
- God,what are you even doing here? - Daddy?
- 我讓你在車媯左 - JD 過來
- I told you to wait in the car. - J.D.,come here.
求你了 讓他過來吧
Please,just let him come here.
你覺得我會傷害我的親生兒子麼?
You think that I would hurt my own son?
顯然 你什麼都幹的出來
Well,you're obviously capable of anything.
求你了 Bill 他沒必要看到我們這樣
Please,bill,he doesn't need to see this.
你覺得你還能瞞多久 Hunter?
How long did you think you were gong to get away with this,hunter?
- Bill 我們走吧 - 你倆都給我閉嘴!
- Bill,let's just leave. - Just stop talking,both of you!
- Bill - 閉嘴!
- Bill. - Shut up!
我們看到有輛車在街道盡頭  還有一輛在車道上
We got a car down the street and one in the driveway.
兩個車牌號都是妻子名下的
Both plates match the wife's name.
記住 堶惘陪茪E歲的男童  我不想讓他看到自己的家人受傷害
Remember,there's a 9-year-old boy in there And I wouldn't put it past him to hurt his own family.
- 或他自己受傷 - 好的 我們從後面進去 你們準備好了麼?
- Or himself. - Ok,we'll take the back. You ready?
- Bill! - 你真他媽的混帳東西 Hunter
- Bill! - You really are a son of a bitch,hunter.
Bill 隨便叫什麼了
Bill-- Whatever!
Bill 我們走吧
Bill. Let's just go.
閉嘴! 閉嘴!
Shut up! Shut up!
爸爸!
Daddy!
不要 JD!
No. J.D.!
FBI 把你的手舉起來
Fbi. Put your hands in the air.
- 我的天啊 - 請退後
- Oh,my god. - Please step back.
Bill 放開他
Bill,let him go.
讓孩子去他媽媽那兒  把你的手舉起來
Let the boy go to his mother and put your hands up.
要保住所有這些謊言 你一定很累了
You must be tired, keeping up with all these lies.
- 你不必這麼做了 - 放開他
- You don't need to do this anymore. - Let him go.
Bill 求你了 放開他
Bill,please let him go.
爸爸...
daddy...
JD...
J.D...
去媽媽那兒 好嗎?
Go to your mom,ok?
去你媽媽那兒
Go to your mom.
- 寶貝 過來 - 把手舉起來
- Sweetie,come here. - Put your hands up.
把手舉起來
Put your hands up.
別那麼做!
don't do that!
把手從口袋堮野X來!
Take your hands out of your pockets!
不要!
Don't!
"哦 當我們第一次學會欺騙 我們得編織一張多麼混亂的網啊"
"oh,what a tangled web we weave When first we practice to deceive."
沃爾特·司各特 (蘇格蘭歷史小說家 詩人)
Sir walter scott.
你覺得這都是我丈夫一個人幹的?
Do you think my husband did all this?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
那個和我一起生活了10年的男人 多麼慈愛而又紳士
The man I lived with for 10 years Was loving and gentle.
他幹不了的
He isn't capable of this.
關於他 我們還有很多不知道的
There's more about him that we don't know.
你必須要有心理準備
You should be prepared.
你會被要求作詳細的筆錄
You're going to be interviewed in detail.
現在我想帶我兒子回家
Right now I want to take my son home.
好的 我會安排人送你回去
Ok. I'll have someone drive you.
媽咪!
Mommy!
哦 媽媽在這兒 親愛的
Oh,mommy's here,baby.
你知道你爸爸愛你勝過一切 是嗎?
You know your daddy loved you more than anything,right?
我知道
I know.
你想把這些放哪兒?
So where do you want these?
我無所謂
I don't care.
你還好吧?
Are you ok?
我以為他帶了武器
I thought he had a weapon.
是的 你那一槍還是情有可原
Yeah. That was a justified shot.
他為什麼要那麼做? 他有妻兒
Why did he do that? He had a wife,a son.
那樣的男人 他喜歡他的車  他的房子 他的生活方式
A guy like that, He likes his car,his house,his lifestyle.
他知道自己在牢堬V不好的
He knew he wasn't going to do well in prison.
所以 他決定了他自己的命運
So he decided his own fate.
我甚至都還不知道他的真名
I never even found out his real name.
這還重要麼?
Does it matter?